<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>pixelzerg.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://pixelzerg.github.io/</link>
   <description>A website of games, code, how tos, language, music, 3D modeling and animating, general art, literature, etc. Anything that I, and hopefully you, find interesting.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> PixelZerg</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>ASComputingExercises - Introduction</title>
	  <link>/ASComputingExercises</link>
	  <author>PixelZerg</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-28T12:05:47+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/ASComputingExercises</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So here&#39;s an explanation of what these posts are all about and why I made them.</p>

<p>All of posts in this section will be my answers to exercises from a textbook:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>AQA Computing AS level - Kerboodle by Sylvia Langfield and Kevin Bond</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The book, I feel, teaches a much more basic level of computing knowledge than that I already own and the exercises are similar to the stuff I was making nore than 3 years ago, when my computing knowledge was much more limited. Even so, I will work through the book because I have never really looked at coding/computing in an acadamic sense before - I learnt all the knowledge I have about coding today from making random projects and experimenting a lot. I did coding simply because I thought it was very interesting and fun. Another reason for going through this book anyway would be because I was not able to find any higher level books in my school library, from which I got this book.</p>

<p>In all of the exercises that I do complete in this book, I aim to write appropriate comments and give appropriate names to variables. Since I learnt coding just by experimenting, I don&#39;t usually write comments and I often use variablenames that other coders may not understand. I will make it so that the code for these exercises are easily understandable by other coders and I will refrain from using confusing indentations. i.e, no more of this (not that it is in my coding that much anyway):</p>

<pre>
Console.WriteLine(
new foo((
banana+1)/(
(moo)-(noo)).method(banana,(foo/loo),gaaaaa)
).Get()
)
</pre>

<p>In adition, I shall make the programs that I make in this section as efficient as possible, which has never been THAT high of a priority for me (it was prioritised, just not as the <em>highest</em> priority).</p>

<p>NB: The answers to the exercises will be completed in <strong>C#</strong></p>

<hr>

<!-- footer -->

<p>Time taken to write: 30 or so min.</p>

<hr>

<!-- Ack -->

<p><small><small><small><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/wneuheisel/5256103622">Cover Image</a> by William Neuheisel. It has not been edited.</small></small></small></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
