<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>pixelzerg.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://pixelzerg.github.io/</link>
   <description>A website of games, code, how tos, language, music, 3D modeling and animating, general art, literature, etc. Anything that I, and hopefully you, find interesting.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> PixelZerg</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Focus</title>
	  <link>/Focus</link>
	  <author>PixelZerg</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-08T08:23:01+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/Focus</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So many projects yet so little time.</p>

<p>Ok, so the amount of projects I am simultaneously doing is getting quite crazy now:
<ol>
<li>Universal Program</li>
<li>MATH calculator</li>
<li>Jeff2</li>
<li>Code Complexifier</li>
<li>AS Computing Exercises</li>
<li>PixelOS</li>
<li>Various stuff on this website (parallax, syntax highlighting, css, etc)</li>
</ol>
(These are the projects that I have worked on for &gt;5 hours in the past few days - so not including stuff like Dungeon Notif, VTPX, Poem Editor, Batch to C#, etc, etc)</p>

<p>School is busy as ever and I really can&#39;t do so many things at once. Let&#39;s choose one program and work on only one.
Rather than leaving them unfinished and moving on to newer projects - let&#39;s see how long I can keep at it and how awesome I can make it.</p>

<h3>Pick a project, any project</h3>

<p>Which one shall we choose?
<h4>Jeff2</h4>
Jeff2 isn&#39;t looking that good at the moment. While it is working great and has great potential and looks good, I think I may have to re-write the file handling system for it some time. For now - <var>ain&#39;t nobody got time for dat</var></p>

<h4>Code Complexifier</h4>

<p>Let&#39;s face it, this project is just a proof of concept and it doesn&#39;t have any real-world uses at all, nobody wan&#39;t their code to be inefficient and if they wanted to make it unreadable and complex, they will most likely are going to use an obfuscator. I probably won&#39;t be working on this project anymore anytime soon...</p>

<h4>AS Computing Exercises</h4>

<p>Doing these exercises aren&#39;t really helping me at all. The exercises are plain and far too easy and therefore boring. Even with my attempts to make them more interesting (as you saw in the blog posts for it). We need something more challenging and interesting, I think.</p>

<h4>PixelOS</h4>

<p>This project is quite interesting so far. I might continue working on it every now and again. I&#39;ve only recently started this project, however (it does not even have a blog post so far), and so I don&#39;t really know if I will end up dropping the project. Let&#39;s wait and find out.</p>

<h4>Universal Program. I CHOOSE YOU!</h4>

<p>My projects for the past few years have been strictly in C#. Let&#39;s try something new! That sounds exciting to me! Recently, I&#39;ve started seeing the positives in Python more and more and there are so many programing languages I want to try out. Let&#39;s do this! My initial breifing does, however, seem a bit ambitious. It might need some toning down.</p>

<h5>But at the end of the day,</h5>

<p>Christmas holidays are comming up. So is a lot of more free time! I think I am going to devote that time to the PixelOS, UniversalProgram and website projects. Ok, i&#39;m focused now!</p>

<h3>PS</h3>

<p>I&#39;ve noticed that my posts are very, very long and I seem to like ranting a lot. I&#39;m going to try and write less or at least split my posts into readable chunks from now on. Also, I&#39;m going to try making stuff about not just coding. I am a fan of some good ol&#39; poetry, gaming, art, languages, etc as well you know!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
